A lot of time people start videos saying,
"I've worked with over 10,000 clients,
I've generated over $9 billion in revenue,
and I know so much
about marketing,
you should join my course."
But the truth is, 10 years ago, I was
living at home with my mom and dad,
driving a very old Volkswagen Polo,
which had been written off before,
which meant
I got a good deal on it.
I lived most of my life in Monzo
overdraft.
And to afford my ticket to move to
Australia,
I had to sell the best part of half
an ounce of MDMA. Sorry, mom.
But Metropolitan Police,
if you're watching this, I
sold it, I got out. I realized what I
was doing was bad, and I knew it had gone
from just taking care of my friends to
dealing, full-blown dealing.
That's the stage everyone goes through in
life in their mid-20s, isn't it?
I now run several multimillion-dollar
businesses. How?
I'm not quite sure.
I live on a quiet beach in Australia.
I'm barefoot all the time,
and I only wear underwear
when I train jujitsu.
Rest of the time, just free balling.
Those things you might want to aspire for
because it's a bit weird.
But yesterday,
I made $32,000 from a single YouTube
video in 24 hours. The best part's this.
You can tell I haven't scripted this part
of the video.
I went on to a website I use called
RevTrack to see if the video had worked,
and I was there psychologically ready to
say, "If there's zero sales there, I'm
just going to delete the video
and pretend it never happened." So as I'm
loading
the browser, I think to myself, "Okay,
James, there's a chance there could be
zero." 32,000. Are you mental? Now,
one of the lessons we get into,
that 32,000 U.S. dollars of rev,
about half of it makes its way back to me.
Our return on ad spend's been a bit smelly
in February.
I think out of every dollar we spend,
we're only making $1.20 back.
Sometimes that can be two and a half,
three.
It's what we call a ROAS,
return on ad spend.
Staff costs are pretty expensive at the
moment.
Hired some people to help me in the
mentorship.
So that 32K, I'd be lucky to see 16.
Then various other
costs. When that 16 comes to me, oh,
who's that? Australian Tax Office.
They'll have eight.
So I'm left with 8 grand, which
is still quite a lot, to be
perfectly honest. But this video
is about how you can make your first
$100,000.
Now,
we're not just going to be talking about
rev, we're going to be talking about
profit.
And I actually watched an Alex Hormozi
video yesterday.
This is going to sound really mean.
I don't watch his content because I like
his content.
I watch his content just to see what the
other competitors are doing. Keeping tabs.
What you scoundrels chat and gas about.
But he made a point
that he's earned a lot of money in his
life, and the richest he
ever felt was earning $100,000.
And I actually resonated with
that quite a lot to
the point I paused his video and I go,
"Listen, you long-haired fuck,
I'm going to
make a better version."
And I'm going to be the guy who can
breathe through his
nose without a nose strip,
be on less steroids than you,
and have a much worse
hairline. So this 100K, I think,
is a psychological safety net.
It's the best way we can explain it.
There's a part of you that thinks,
"Now I've got 100K.
If everything implodes tomorrow,
I'm off to Asia to smash broo— to
tan and live a life." Because I've
backpacked Asia before, back
in my day, 2010. I went for six months,
spent £3,500,
including flights.
So there's a part of you, 100K,
you kind of sit back and go, "If
it all goes to shit,
I'm off to Pattaya." That's a joke.
Where's the area full of all the birds?
Not Bangkok, not the islands.
What are the seediest parts of Thailand?
Pattaya, I've actually never been.
Bangkok? Come on, come on.
Phuket, that's the place.
My fiancée won't mind me saying
this. I hope she knows. Basically,
when I was in my early 20s,
I went there, genuinely to get a massage,
and it turned out to be more than a
massage,
and it was an interesting experience,
to say the very least.
Anyway, so let's think of
that psychological safety net of 100K.
So some of you might be quite far off,
some of you might be working towards it.
I'm going to be giving you loads of advice
like an older brother. That's what I am.
I've been through most of the things
you're going through.
So whether you're at 1K, 5K, 10K a month,
I've been there.
There was a point
that to go into my training app full time,
Jameswith Academy, I
had to give up my online PT one-to-one
clients.
That was making me like £4,000 a week.
Then before that,
I had to give up my face-to-face coaching
to
go in all online. And then before that,
I had to give up working in recruitment to
become a bloody personal trainer.
There's an amount of leaps
that you have to take to get to the next
step.
But you have to get to a position where
you kind of force your own hand, where you
think, "Okay,
I have to now make this jump.
I now have to quit my job.
I now have to move into this new realm of
work." And I'm going to give you some
tips and tricks to force your own hand so
that you actually do it.
100K is the escape velocity. It
is the amount of money you need
for peace of mind to know this is working,
to know that if there's a downturn in
sales,
you're still going to be okay for a few
months. Imagine that.
Having 100K means sales really soften for
three months.
You can, in your own time, just get
that engine up and running again.
Because momentum is a big part of
business.
My podcast,
before I shut it down three years ago,
was doing $100,000 and
$150,000 an episode.
Now it's less than that,
but who am I to think
it's just going to come back?
I have to grease the wheels, get it going,
build
momentum algorithmically, socially,
psychologically,
and get things moving again.
Same in business.
So many of you that hired business
mentors, I'm sure over the years,
got you to
sell three,
six months of business up front.
You get this amazing looking month,
and then suddenly three months down the
line,
you're like, "Hold on.
Where's my revenue?" You became complacent
because you got
such a big number in the early months
that you think you could've taken your
foot
off the gas,
and you pay the price having to put the
foot back down and realizing
that it takes months of nurturing new
leads to get them into buy.
So having that 100K means,
"Do you know what?
I fucked up,
but I'm okay for a few months." There's
also seasonal periods of
motivation running a business people don't
talk about.
There are months where I'm like, "Yeah,
boy." There are other months where I'm
like, "I can't be fucked."
But in those periods,
I've got the effort from the
previous months that I can monetize,
whether it's through the months before,
I was
churning out a lot of content,
the months after, paid ads do well.
I'm touring with Chris Williamson in a few
weeks.
My output is going to go down,
but I know that all the goodwill
that I generate in
the weeks while I was good, while I
was on top, while I'm at my studio,
while I can
film, it's going to come to fruition.
Now, before we get into the main lessons,
we're going to go down memory lane.
Now, Declan,
there could be some dodgy shit here, bro,
so hopefully you don't
expose me. Oh,
there's me coming up on a pill at
Kolsch at Tobacco Docks.
It's not what I was looking for.
So just to show you, we
are at 3rd of October, 2016, and this
is where my content journey began.
I'm in a PT room of a Budget Gym.
I am Explaining a Snickers protein bar.
A second take because someone came in
and interrupted me.
Or just putting content out.
At this point,
living at home with my parents, driving
a beaten-up Volkswagen Polo,
I'm getting into my content game.
Were these videos amazing? Absolutely not.
Here's a funny one.
This is me on my way to Australia.
I'm actually on my way to Bali, one-way
backpacking.
Read a book called "The Magic of Thinking
Big." It wasn't that good a
book, but it had me in
that mindset of where I was like, "Oh,
do you know what?
I think I want more for my life."
Actually, the interesting thing is, I took
this picture outside a Budget Gym in
Bracknell, 2016, and
I put the caption on this as,
"On to bigger things." Now,
I had no idea how
big those things were going to be.
I never thought I would fly business
class,
never thought I'd operate a business,
never thought I'd have staff.
I never thought I'd sell a book
or any of these things.
So at that point,
I sometimes wonder what
that geezer there was
thinking. This was my business class.
A pair of rugby shorts, wired headphones,
and I'm in three seats to myself on
Garuda Airlines. First beer in Bali,
staying in a hostel. I was studying.
2016,
I was inside another mentorship at the
time.
So what was going to bring us on to lesson
number one?
This is here I am with my mate Josh.
We're in the WIT Sundays. Funnily enough,
I'm wearing a black G-Shock watch there.
I had that timed to one minute, so
when I was with my clients,
I'd just press beep,
and yeah. Number one,
thank God I started an email list sooner.
So when I was on my way to Australia,
I thought, "I'm going to go to Bali for a
bit, then I'm going to go to Australia,
and I'm going to travel the East Coast so
I
can see where I want to live." So I went
to Cairns and made my way down.
Here, doing the WIT Sundays. What
was crazy was I had been selling, or
trying to sell,
digital products to my audience for ages.
And I started email marketing about a year
before I left for Australia.
I sent one email to about 3,000 people
going, "Do you want to work with me
one-to-one?" And 10 people said yes at
£50.
So I was making £500 a week doing online
PT whilst traveling.
Now,
even though that's a pretty decent amount
of money, in today's terms, probably
about 750,
I still stayed in hostels with 14 people.
I still lived small.
The saying is, "Small enough, long enough,
big enough, soon
enough." So I wasn't flashy by any means.
This is a drinking game called the Grand
National.
So I'm not even
working for the boat, but as you can see,
I've got the whole crowd here going.
When it comes to drinking games,
I've got a black belt in drinking games
already.
These are the best years of my life,
to having a family, of course.
Look at that.
That is ketamine, cocaine, and MDMA.
Told you.
There was a little dealing phase,
but allegedly. My mate Lucy Lord.
So she was staying with me recently.
Trying to help her with her business at
the moment.
She was working in pharmaceuticals
when I met her.
I'm on a wall of fame at Massive Wieners
for doing a one-meter hot dog in three
minutes 46. What can I say? I
was literally just working outside
cafes, old MacBook,
servicing those 10 clients,
putting out content
every day. This dog,
I put on my Facebook
that I needed somewhere to live, and
two of my followers said I could move in
with them.
So I lived in Manly for a bit just to save
money. It was $300 a week, £150 a week.
Then I started in Fitness First, which
was interesting.
I had to start as part of a franchise,
which I haven't really told many people
about before.
So because I couldn't really afford to pay
the rent, I started in
Fitness First on a franchise where my rent
got paid, but I had to give 50% of
everything I earned to the franchise,
which was interesting.
We're going to get to the important part
in a second, but for me, it was just about
establishing myself,
getting into a gym where I could start
doing face-to-face.
But the funny thing is,
I met Durin inside the gym,
my Turkish mate, and he was
like: "What are you doing?" He's like:
"You're coming into the gym.
We all want to find a way out." I told him
I was making £500 a week.
He was like: "Why are you here?" He
was like: "You're doing the one thing
that none
of us can do." He couldn't get his head
around it.
Here's me celebrating 9,000 followers,
and that's on Facebook
as well. I think this
is one of my first videos
that kind of went viral.
Again, 37,000 views. For me, that
was massive.
Put a little boost on it.
9th of April 2017, I eventually went
and bought a MacBook
that I could edit on.
So the thing I want to make clear here is,
up until this
point, all of my videos
were livestreams because I didn't know how
to
edit and I didn't have a camera.
So as you see here,
my followers started going up.
I was at 12,000 followers.
Because I didn't have access to a camera,
I didn't know how to edit,
I didn't know how to use Premiere Pro
or any of those
things, I just went live every day.
So going live every day
is pretty exhausting.
It's pretty hard. All these videos I
was doing, I'm just going live.
So you guys have got access to make Reels,
you can edit inside your phone.
Back when I started,
that wasn't an option.
The reason I'm wearing a Fitness First
shirt is I've just come home from PT-ing
all
day to come back and make a video.
12,000 likes.
That's what it was before followers.
And every day was just putting out
content.
Now,
the content wasn't particularly great.
It would be between clients,
I'd be walking around, whatever it was.
So like some of you might think
that I make incredible content now.
Thank you.
So flattering. But this
is really what it looked like in the early
stages.
This is me working towards my first 100K.
Every day, wherever I was going, I
was recording content.
There was just no excuse to not put out
videos every single day, just getting the
repetitions in. Even at my parents' house,
sat on bed. What was I talking about?
Something about books that I was reading,
trainers.
I don't even know what
that fucking clip was about, but it
was relentless.
I would go live at every opportunity
because you can be busy and make good
money,
or you can be broke with loads of spare
time. There's no in between.
And because I was broke, there
was just no excuse not to be churning out
content.
And again, I'm not saying it
was the best quality content ever,
I'm just saying
that I was so proactive with it.
Anywhere I was, cafe,
client asked me a question,
make it a video, post it.
I remember even I
was explaining to a client what valgus
knee meant,
and I would just take pictures of my legs.
[chuckles] I sat there,
just anything I could do for content,
I would do it.
And I think that everyone seems to think
that all of their content needs to be
perfect. We've gone from 10K,
now we're at 20K.
When I was with my clients,
I would film them,
then I'd make videos out of the
technique. And to me, looking at this,
this was, so for years, my following
was niche. It took me, what,
four years to get to 10K?
Every time I posted, I
was feeding something, an algorithm.
I was feeding the pony, as I call it now.
Then when I hit 25,000 followers, that
was when I got the
MacBook, the camera, the microphone,
the tripod. Stage one.
25,000 followers before I even considered
getting a camera.
The first thing, this
is my first money that I ever had.
Nowhere near 100K.
That is a secondhand camera.
I had to get a memory card.
I had to go to a camera store.
So any of you out there
that want to step up your
production from where you
are to where you want to be next,
go to a secondhand
camera store, get a secondhand camera,
because you don't care
if it's pre-owned or
not. You just care that it does the job.
And I still didn't know how to edit.
So my first video
that I posted had gaps in it.
I didn't cut or do jump cuts.
I still didn't really understand what I
was doing
with it. Then this
is an interesting picture here.
So where I talk about staying small, I
was starting to earn good money here.
Probably coming close to 1,000 pounds a
week.
And I flew to Australia one way with Air
China, and I had to sit on the floor for
10 hours in Beijing. And even though I
was making good money, I still flew Air
China on the way home because I had the
return leg.
Because I hadn't got that 100K yet,
I still lived small.
I know now you can see the fancy cars
and the jets and Neotonic, all of
that stuff.
But even here,
that's my mom's old suitcase.
[chuckles] Me in Beijing Airport reading a
book.
And at 25,000 followers,
I did my first seminar,
which I rented out a hotel
room at Bracknell.
The reason I did my first seminar
was I wanted to expense my
flight home.
So my flight with Air China
was 500 pounds return from the UK to
Australia. And I thought
if I put some event in the diary,
I can expense the
flight.
I'll say I came back to do the trip.
So 180 people came to that, which
is incredible.
My manager actually saw this
and reached out to work with me because he
was like,
"If there's someone there working
and doing events off his own back,
imagine what
it could be like with some help." Now,
let me show you something.
I went to a festival in Croatia called
Ultra and got absolutely
obliterated for a week.
And then we did Cell Week afterwards,
which was fucking
mental. My come down was so bad,
I bought a first class flight back to
Australia.
Now,
any of you that have flown with Etihad,
you get an apartment, which is pretty
cool.
And I hit 60,000 followers on the plane.
But let me tell you why this is stupid.
So the flight was 5,000 pounds.
I bought it one way. If I'd got it return,
it probably would've been about 5,500.
It probably would've been 10% more to go
both ways. So I wasted five grand there.
Then I get back to my apartment in Sydney
and realize my bed was
$170.
So I've spent five grand on a flight to
come home to
a bed that I got for $170.
Then my setup was living in an
apartment that cost me 700 pounds a month
with a camera that I got secondhand on
my balcony,
and I went live every single morning
and just made content from the
balcony.
There is a ping pong table behind me.
I live in a lads' pad.
And it wasn't what I was saying, it
was how often I was getting content out
there.
I would make content about absolutely
anything.
Here you can see I'm making a fucking
video about whey protein.
I'd go live every single day from the same
spot.
600 people watching there.
Then I would go to the gym.
In between clients,
I'd film content with Darren.
Everything here works backwards from
content. Go home, film another module.
On the balcony, content. Go inside,
film another module, film another video.
Whatever I could,
I would just put out content every single
day.
And the thing is,
you see the part of it now where you might
see, "Oh, he's doing
well," or whatever.
But I thought today would be the best way.
We haven't even got into how you make your
100K yet.
You need to see the amount of content
that is required.
[chuckles] Because even if we look here,
I just hit 100K. It's 2017.
Continue to put out content, images,
whatever it is.
Every single day, it's so imperative
that you just keep putting out content.
Then if we go to February 2018, Darren
and I...
I broke up with my missus. I
was on a visa, so I had to leave.
We went to Bali,
and we shared a hotel room with two twin
beds.
At this point, I'm 27, 28. The hotel
was 20 pound a night.
We could have our own room. But for us,
it was about keeping costs low,
pumping out
content, keeping costs low,
pumping out content.
Even here, doing a live,
sat on a bed in a hotel.
So this brings me onto really point two.
I had to show you instead of just telling
you.
You need to post daily,
and you need to put out so much content
over the years.
And it's not actually
that the content you're putting out
is making that much of a
difference. The real truth is that
that content is making you
better at content.
Before we even talk about money,
before we even talk about what
you charge,
it's imperative you understand that.
Every video you put out doesn't just make
you more competent at making content.
Every single video performance
is giving you feedback on what works
and what
doesn't.
And that is the only way to determine your
content style, your
content cadence,
the stuff you're going to talk about,
and the stuff you're not.
So notoriously,
every time I talk about muscle growth,
I would get abuse for it, so
therefore,
I don't talk about muscle growth.
Then when I talked about fat loss
and I was evidence-based
and I used analogies,
things would go well.
But it's only through thousands of
repetitions that I was
able to get to that conclusion.
Lesson number three, there
is not just one type of
content. So as you can see from there,
there were static posts, there were posts
with text, there were carousels,
there were reels, there were landscape,
there was
portrait.
There needs to be so many different
variations of content that you put
out on a regular basis so
that you can understand what works well
for what
platform, what medium. And
if you're going to make
that piece of content, it has to
go on Instagram, on Facebook, on TikTok,
on YouTube Shorts.
You should be putting out long form on
YouTube.
Now you should be looking at LinkedIn.
You should be looking at Twitter.
All of these different places.
If you're going to create content, put it
everywhere. And four, from that,
what I wanted you to see was for years,
I lived
within my means. From 2016 when I arrived,
I
was renting with my friends up until 2022.
So for six years, I lived with friends.
Main reason?
Yeah, to hang out with friends,
but also to keep costs down.
When my costs were lower Didn't have a car
till 2023.
But my costs being low, there
was less stress on my business.
I've just got to pay myself,
I can reinvest in equipment, I can travel.
Which again, traveling
was very good for my business because
story views, for
me, go up when I travel. So
when Australia gave me a visa where I had
to leave
every month, I was in Fiji, then I
was in Bali, then I was in New Zealand,
then I
was back in Australia. People
were invested in my brand
and my life because it was
interesting.
And living within your means
is kind of the meta hack in the onset
before you have disposable income.
That 100K,
reaching it in the bank account as fuck
you money is going to be very
difficult if your burn rate
is too high compared to your income.
In the onset,
it's actually counterintuitive to be
spending too much.
And this is another reason,
reason really number five would be
something I call
solopreneuring, which
is where you're a solo entrepreneur.
All the way up until 2023,
I didn't hire a single person.
I had a manager who helped me get gigs
and deals.
So from 2016 to 2023, seven years, edited
everything myself because also it meant I
could turn things around quicker.
I could sit on my bedroom floor,
do an edit,
not send it off to the Philippines and
wait six hours.
I would edit it in 15 minutes
and post it the same day.
I'd post it fucking 15 minutes after the
idea.
Something would come up on the news
and I'd have a video out in 22 minutes.
I'd run home, film it, put it out.
To be a solopreneur means that you're not
bleeding.
Every member of staff you have
is a hole you drill in the bucket
underneath you. And when you get paid,
it just dribbles out.
Which brings me onto lesson number six,
which people don't talk about, is I'm very
anti-agency for a lot of things because
someone comes along and goes, "We'll do
all of your marketing for you." You don't
actually want that because the second you
stop paying them,
they stop doing the marketing for you.
For me, doing all of this stuff myself,
doing my own editing, doing my own reels,
doing my own posting schedules,
learning all these things,
I became an expert in
marketing. Because
if you're going to pay someone to do
something, this blends into
solopreneuring and living within your
means.
If you're going to pay someone to do it,
you're not going to learn it.
Now, recently I worked with a business
and it was very clear that they
worked with a lot of creators who didn't
really understand the game.
And when they started working for me,
I started going, "Hold on.
That's not right.
Hold on.
That thumbnail shouldn't look like that.
Who picked that title?" The majority of
their clients that would use them wouldn't
have spotted those things.
When you become your own agency
and you learn everything
yourself and you implement it yourself,
you learn what's good and what's bad.
If you get an agency
or you hire people to make these problems
go away, you become
dependent.
And becoming dependent on an ongoing cost
is an inefficient way to run a
business.
So once we have all of those things clear,
we should pretty much map out
your first few years. Post daily.
When you can get better equipment, do it.
Go to a secondhand camera store.
Mix up different types of content.
Make sure you get a piece of content out
every day.
Try and keep the team to one as long as
you can.
Learn the trade so you can control every
single element of marketing and not become
dependent on agencies.
Then we can get into the next really
important part of
earning your first 100K,
and it's what I call commoditization.
So you must cap and limit the amount of
work you can do.
Because you're working on your own
and you've got the edits,
you've got delivering
to your clients,
you've got all your different things as a
coach.
There's only a certain amount of clients
you can work with before there is a case
of diminishing returns. You must mark
that out, write it down, and make it 50
or 30
or 20 or 10, whatever it is.
Then once you hit that amount,
you put your rates
up.
And we're going to be living in a
never-ending balance between increasing
rates
and dropping clients.
So this confuses a lot of people.
There are two golden rules to running a
good business, your first 100K as a coach.
If you're not full,
you're not marketing hard enough.
There's no excuses you could tell me.
If you're marketing hard enough,
you'd be full.
But then the second rule is
if you're full,
you need to increase prices.
Then when you increase prices,
some people drop off, and then
when you drop off,
you're not full,
so you need to start marketing again.
Now,
the best way for you to think about this
is a hotel.
When a hotel has lots of spare rooms,
it doesn't charge a lot.
When a hotel only has three rooms left,
it can charge whatever it wants.
Commoditization.
A hotel room doesn't have inherent value.
It has value timesed by the amount of
people that want it.
So if you want a hotel room,
it's going to be here.
But if Taylor Swift's playing in town,
The hotel room stays the same,
the staff stay the same.
Everything stays the same.
Demand is the changing factor.
Same with flights.
You want to go on holiday with your
family, cool. The flight's this.
Oh, bank holiday, it's now this.
So demand is the factor that determines
how much people pay for the same thing,
the same service, whatever.
And your demand is going to be created
through social media.
It's going to be created through putting
out posts.
It's going to be created through getting
data from people and all of those four S's
that I speak about in other videos.
Social, squeeze, sell, scale.
So let's do some maths for a second.
So as a coach,
I think you should charge weekly.
I think weekly is a real nice way for
revenue.
When you charge monthly,
people can compare it to their mortgage
and other bills
that are quite like credit card, mortgage,
whatever.
Weekly costs can feel more like a gym
where you do classes, or it can feel more
like going out with friends,
socializing at dinner.
We think of expendable costs as weekly
costs and then important costs as
monthly costs.
I think that's just the psychology of it.
So I think that most of you should try
and charge your hourly rate for a
week to begin with as a starting wage.
So whatever you would coach someone for an
hour of your time is what you're going
to charge them for a week,
and then you're going to try
and service that person
under an hour. If it's different to that,
it's different to that.
I appreciate that.
So let's use a personal trainer
or a physio as an example.
Let's say you're charging £40 an hour.
You can maybe bring
that person on at £40 a week.
So with that in mind,
and let's maybe convert
that into US dollars in a
second,
how many clients would you need per week
at what
price point to have $100,000 revenue?
Now, let's assume
that 30% of all of your operating
costs are going to be expenses,
whether it's your phone bill, it's your
equipment, it's your camera,
it's your microphone,
it's the filming studio you hire
once a week for two hours to batch film
some content.
It's the podcast studio you're hiring for
whatever.
So let's do some quick maths to how much
that would equate to into clients.
So if we think about it, let's say £40,
£45 is $50 US.
People love US dollars,
so that's $50 per client per session.
If you were to have 40 clients at $50 an
hour, that's
$104,000 a year. So over time,
if you can get your weekly rate
to $75 a week, which isn't crazy,
with 40 clients, that's
$156,000 a year.
So that's all your costs
and 100K in your pocket.
Now, 40 clients can seem like a lot,
but it's also not.
If you have 4,000 followers,
that's just 1% of your audience.
So once you reach that 100K,
I would put it in this scale because you
don't really
need to hoard 100K.
But the first thing you should look at
is equipment upgrades.
When you can get a better microphone,
a better camera, a better tripod, that's
going to be an investment
that in real time is going to increase
your reach, the
quality of your content,
the amount of people that
are going to see it.
That's going to be one of your best return
on investments.
Once you have all your equipment
and everything in your solopreneurial
business
sorted,
that's where I'd maybe look to delegate
some stuff.
What I would say is a staff upgrade.
So maybe hire a contractor for thumbnails,
maybe to do some simple editing because
you can free up some time to service
clients or create more content.
But the very last stage
that you want to jump into is lifestyle.
The lifestyle is the last part. When I
was still only just getting by,
I had my skateboard, I had the beach,
I had my laptop, I had my clients,
I had my
tripod.
I watched the same things on Netflix.
I had the same iPhone as most people.
For years, my life
was incredibly ordinary.
I was just having a lot of people see my
videos.
Unfortunately, I've scaled this so far,
unfortunately, that I've now got like
four or five businesses that I'm running.
And now, to be perfectly honest with you,
a lot of my day-to-day lifestyle sucks
I'm on calls late in the evening.
I'm having to manage different things.
Because of that, I need a 911 GT3.
Because of that, I need to fly
business class. Because of that,
I need to have the fancy house.
Because of that, I need the Rolex.
The 100K part is the best part.
It's the least stressful.
It's the most fun creating content.
You should be so excited.
The lifestyle upgrades only come
when you scale your
business into the shittosphere.
Because from naught to one million
is the best
time ever. From one to 15 million
is the graveyard.
I'm in the graveyard right now because I'm
rich enough to really want nice things,
but poor enough that I still can't stop
working.
And maybe now I'm in 10 years in the
graveyard, I might escape the graveyard,
or I
might go back down to being poor. But
if I could start all over again, I would
start email marketing this second.
Because the best time to start email
marketing was probably 10 years ago,
but the
second-best time is today.
I would post daily no matter what.
Starting from zero,
there would be no excuse not to post
daily.
I would mix up different types of content,
podcasts, YouTube, clips, short-form,
long-form, everything you can. Blogs,
LinkedIn, everything.
I would live well within my means for
years, and I would enjoy it.
I used to wear stuff from Cotton On,
which is the cheapest shop you can get in
Australia.
I'd buy my T-shirts from Uniqlo
or fucking AS 色 ler, whatever it
is. I still do. I would solopreneur.
I would keep the team a number of one for
as long as possible.
Then I would learn the trade for years.
I would not let anyone else run my ads,
do my editing, do anything else.
I would learn every component of my
business, so if anyone came along
and tried to
teach me how to do it different, I'd know,
and I could sniff bullshit.
And then I would commoditize.
I would set a finite amount of people
that I'm going
to work with.
I would then increase demand,
and every time I'm full, I'd increase
my rates. And I would try
and exponentially increase
that as long as I can.
You wouldn't need to change
that until well over 100K.
I'd work out the maths.
How many clients do I need at what price
point?
Then I would just keep working to get to
that client, increase my price point every
time using the demand
that we spoke about before.
My first upgrades would be equipment.
My second upgrades would be delegation
through staff.
My third and final upgrade probably isn't
going to happen for seven to 10 years,
would be lifestyle. But
if you get those fundamentals right,
the first 100K comes
easier than you could ever imagine.
But you must be prepared to post for ages.
The reason I showed you so much in the
beginning was it took me years of living
modestly, being a madman.
If you'd met me in 2018, you would've
thought I was insane. You would've gone,
"This weirdo talks to himself on his
phone. He's only got a handful of clients,
and he's only got a handful of
followers." It takes years for this stuff
to start working, and the sooner you can
appreciate that, the better. Now,
those are just some ramblings of lessons
off the
top of my head.
If you want to work with me,
I teach people how to get from zero to
10K, 10 to 100K, and 100K to a million.
There's going to be a link in the
description if you want to work with me.
And if you're not convinced and you go,
"Yeah, mate, I like what you're saying,
but
I'm not fully convinced
and you're a coach," then check out this
video here where I
give you a full blueprint of how to run an
online personal training business.
So if you're a normal coach, work with me.
If you're a personal trainer,
check out this first.